Traders, in today's video, we're going
to talk about the different entry models
for smart money concepts. I'm going to
be touching the four popular entry
models. We have the order block, fair
value gap, breaker blocks, and flip
zones. And I'm going to break this video
into parts. So, in today's video, we're
going to focus more on order blocks. So,
make sure you subscribe, turn on the
notification bell so that you'll be
notified when other videos will drop and
be updated. You get the point? So let's
go to the chart guys and point out valid
order blocks together and also how to
take smart entries from this order
blocks. Let's go to the chart guys. So
traders let's get to understand the idea
behind order block and what it means. So
from what I have here on the screen, you
can see that an order block is a price
zone on the chart where big financial
institutions, you know, like banks,
hedge funds, etc. placed large buy or
sell orders leaving behind a strong
footprint. So having in mind that
autoblock you know this is actually and
I I will call it the most popular entry
point for smart money concept strategy
and I use it too and um at the end of
this video I'll get to show you how you
know I map it out on the chart and you
know take my entries things I look out
for the order blocks and the rest. So
this is actually an important aspect of
um smart money concept. Once you get to
understand the idea behind order block
and how to strategically map it out then
entries in the market won't be a
problem. So make sure you watch to the
very end. So why is order block
important? Now from here you can see
that order blocks are important because
they show where the strongest players in
the market institutions you know placed
their orders. As you are trying to make
money with your little capital and the
rest we have the market movers you know
those that you know their orders can you
know shake everywhere in the market. So
that's what we mean by you know the
institutions the banks you know central
banks and the rest. So other block will
show where these institutions you know
placed their orders and then since these
players they move millions their
footprints become valuable zones for
traders. So and now price often reacts
when it returns to an order block making
them strong areas for entries, stop-loss
um stop-loss placement and um take
profit targets. So you can see from the
illustration I have here once there is
an order block we get an impulsive move
and that impulsive move will now break a
structure. So the idea will be to wait
for price to come back into that other
block. If the break of structure was to
the upside
we will be looking to buy once price you
know gets back into that other block.
And if the impulsive movement and the
break of structure was to the downside,
we'll be looking to sell once price you
know gets into that order block. So it
is very important. Now let me quickly
show you guys the rules to follow on how
to spot valid blocks. So on how to spot
valid block, I've listed five important
tips here. And number one is the trend
matters. It is important for you to know
where the market is going to the market
structure. Break the market down and
know where it is pointing at so that you
will align. You know the popular
statement the trend is your friend. It
is important you know where the market
is going to so that you will follow suit
because when you are following the trend
the probability of your trend playing
out will be very high than when you are
going against the trend. And then the
last candlestick in an accumulation is
actually the order block. So when you're
trying to map out your order block
inside
a consolidation or accumulation or
inside an origin,
look out for the last candlestick.
That is your order block candlestick.
And now the next one here is breakout
structure. So have it in mind that
before you even start looking for your
order block candlestick, you must have
pointed out a break of structure cuz
once you see a break of structure, the
next question
is what caused the break of structure,
the impulsive move that cleared the
structure, where is it coming from? And
now once you point out the accumulation
that happened before the impulsive move
that caused the break of structure, you
now need to look for the last
candlestick reaction before the
impulsive move. Highlight it because
that is your order block candle. And
it's important you highlight it very
well so that you will not miss out on
your entries and the rest because there
are times price will just come and just
give it a little tapping and move to
your direction and if you don't
highlight it well to place your entries
well you see the market leaving you out
and then you will miss out on trades
that you know would have given you a
good you know massive you know massive
profit and the rest. So make sure you
highlight it well the last candlestick
in an accumulation and have it in mind
that that other block must cause what a
break of structure and it's also
important that you point out imbalance
that is fair value gap what I have here
it's important you point out in balance
very close to the other block because
that will make the order block more
valid you know it will be more strong
you know for you to take trades from
that particular order block because you
know personally for me any order block
that doesn't have imbalance I'm not
really comfortable with it I need to see
that imbalance you know present before I
will tag that other block as valid and
now liquidity must be present before
price will tap into your origin make
sure that you know you've been able to
map out liquidity that price will clear
as it is trying to tap into your origin
because if there is no liquidity your
origin or your other block will be the
liquidity and then you will see price
clearing you out you know hitting the
stop loss before it will still move to
your direction. So make sure there is
all there is liquidity you know price
will clear before it will tap into the
other block. So this is um a bearish
structure and an example of a supply
zone which I have highlighted here. Let
me also show you guys um the example of
a bullish trend. And after that I'll
show you guys you know some of the
treads I've been able to catch using
autoblock. Like I said earlier this
particular entry model I love it and um
is one of the entry models I use you
know to catch my entries. I use order
blocks, you know, more to catch my
entries. So, I'll also show you guys
some of the smart setups I've been able
to, you know, catch using order blocks.
This is an example of a bullish order
block. You can see from the illustration
here, we got a change of character. The
next thing you need to look out for is
where is the accumulation that happened
before the change of character. And now
from that accumulation, you do what? You
look for the last candlestick reaction
before the impulsive move that cleared
and caused that change of character or
break structure. That is what you will
highlight as your order block. And like
I said earlier, your imbalance must be
present, which is what I've also mapped
out here. It's either imbalance or fair
value gap. So you know that's actually
the gap you know price creates in the
market and it's also one of the entry
models which I will be explaining how
you can also catch smart setups using
imbalance in our next video. So make
sure you subscribe and turn on the
notification bell and then liquidity
must be present.
If there is no liquidity you are likely
going to be the liquidity. So make sure
that liquidity price will clear before
tapping into your order block. Let me
show you guys some smart entries I was
able to catch using order block entry
models. If you can remember the first
illustration on how to spot order block,
you can see that this is actually the
entry. Once the breakup structure
happens, just highlight it. The only
thing you need to do is to patiently
wait for price to come and tap into that
particular order block and dish out the
clean movement. Now you can see how
price got there, mitigated the order
block and then moved straight to take
profit. Now when trying to you know put
your stop loss and your take profit
inside the accumulation, look out for
the last week rejection. you know,
you'll put your stop loss a little bit,
you know, above the last week rejection
if you're trying to sell or below the
last week rejection if you're trying to
buy. You know, some people may try to
refine, you know, tighten their stop
loss. But this is how I place my own
stop loss so that I will give the market
you know some breathing space to
um you know dish out good moves cuz I
wouldn't want price to like pack me out
and then dish out the movement when I'm
trying to tighten my stop loss. So this
is how you wait for it. And I know some
traders will be asking why don't you buy
to sell. At the end of the day, you can
still be able to catch the correctional
move because any move that is against
the trend, you call it the correctional
move. So, you can still be able to buy
to sell depending on the confirmation
you've seen. But we are not talking
about correctional move today. I just
want you to understand how to map out
order blocks and how to take smart
entries with order block. So once you
map it out following the rules I stated
earlier. Once you map out your order
blocks, all you just need to do is to
set your pending order and patiently
wait for price to come there, tap you
in, and then dish out good results. Make
sure you apply proper risk management
because you understand that trading is
risky and your capital is at risk. So no
matter how clean you think your setup
is, you can still lose your money. But
at the end of the day, this is a
strategy I've tried out. Um, particular,
you see how it looks. Just this
illustration alone is explaining the
strategy I use because most of my
threads are always from other blocks.
So, let me also show you guys another
entry. So, this is still coming from the
bullish order block that is from the
illustration I showed you guys earlier.
You can still see how price tapped into
the other block and you know boom
straight to TP. So when you're also
trying to set your TP your TP should
always be at a point of reversal. That
is where the correctional movement
started from. That is where you place
your TP because price can come there and
you know retrace almost back to entry.
So it's important for you to be very
realistic when setting your TP. And you
can also see how I placed the stop loss.
I always pay attention to the last week
rejection inside the accumulation and my
stop loss will just be a little bit um
below or above the last week rejection.
Some traders push it just a little bit
below or above the other block, but I
consider the last week rejection. So, it
all depends on the one on how you want
to do it for yourself. You just need to
do your back testing and um make sure
you know what you're doing as you are
taking your trades. So in our next video
I'll be breaking down how to take
entries with the fair value gap.
Remember we are talking about the four
entry models for smart money concept and
u we've been able to tackle that of
other block. This one is pretty much
popular. So in our next video which is
the part two of this particular video
we'll talk about how to catch smart
entries with fair value gap. I'll see
you on the next